なんば　むった
(南波六太)＜宇宙飛行士を
選抜する第３次試験➡
The third astronaut selection exam.
最後の課題は 仲間５人の中から➡
Our final task
was to choose the two best candidates from among our five member team to become astronauts.
宇宙飛行士にふさわしいと思う
者を ２人だけ選ぶことだった＞
ジャンケンで決めようか｡
Let's decide with rock-paper-scissors.
What?!
ふざけてるワケじゃね～ぞ…
マジで言ってんだ｡
This isn't a joke.
I'm serious.
なすだ
(茄子田)ほぉ～ジャンケンかぁ
彼らしいねぇ…ねぇ｡
Rock-paper-scissors, huh?
That sounds just like him...
Yes...
We wanted to end on a happy note,
＜楽しい５人のままで
終わりたくて➡
俺たちは ジャンケンをした＞
so we used
rock-paper-scissors to decide.
And they were our winners...
＜そして 勝ったのは
あの２人だった＞
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
My goal is zero gravity
Space Brothers
Waves of people flood the intersection
Like vague silhouettes they stream past incessantly
How do I look in their midst?
I don't know
Hiding my true intentions desperately
I dish out vague excuses
My ambitions of going to space, harbored for so long,
are frail and brittle
No matter how I turn the globus
I have no home where I end up
There's no point to looking on a map
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
until I can look down on the entire world
I will yell
and scream
with a heart of steel
that I am going to zero gravity
Bar Tipsy
#22 Working on the Dream
I'd like the Spanish fried noodles.
このスペイン風やきそばと…｡
Yes, the Spain noodles.
(店員)はい スペやき｡
あと アボカドサラダ｡
And the avocado salad.
はい｡アボサラ｡
あと…どうしよう➡
Right, the avo salad.
And then...
What do you think?
古谷君の分も
何か注文しとこうか？
Should we order something for Furuya?
(新田)何が好きなんだ アイツは？
What does he like?
う～ん…何だろう？
Hmm, good question...
バナナは好きだろうな やっぱり｡
He probably likes bananas.
⦅ウキー！⦆
すいません 追加でバナナ１本｡
(店員)はい えっと…｡
Excuse me, could we also get one banana?
Yes, um...
そりゃ そのまますぎだろ｡
あるの？
You're making assumptions.
You serve bananas?
はい バナイチ｡
あるんだ…いいかも｡
Yes, one banana.
They have bananas!
I might...
Hey!
おい コラ！
誰がバナナやねん！
Why would I order a banana?
You shouldn't judge people by their looks.
イメージでモノ言うなや ジブン！
《好きじゃねえんだ》
So you don't like bananas...
《まあ 好きやけど…》
Well, I do like bananas...
フフフ…そろったね｡➡
Everyone's here.
じゃあみんな カンパイしよう｡
Okay,
a toast.
２週間お疲れさま｡そして…➡
To all the work everyone did in the last two weeks.
And...
人生をかけた あのジャンケンで
見事ヒューストン行きを決めた➡
To the rock-paper-scissors winners who earned a trip to Houston.
新田君と➡
To Nitta
伊東さんを祝して…｡
and Itou.
カンパイ！
Cheers!
(一同)カンパーイ！
おめでとう！
Cheers!
Congrats!
おめでとう｡
Congratulations.
Thank you for waiting.
(店員)お待たせしました｡どうぞ｡
Here you are.
せめて切ろうや…｡
You could have sliced it or something.
Eggs and
Bacon
and Eggs
Eggs and
Bacon
and Eggs
Recommended!!
Chef's Choice Salad
おっちゃん 俺なぁ ﾁﾝﾊﾟﾝｼﾞｰとな
大食い対決したってん｡
So, Pops, I once had an eating contest with a chimp.
What?
＜せりかさんはこの日➡
They can be pretty...
Serika looked a little apologetic that night.
少し申し訳なさそうな
顔をしていた＞
＜新田のヤロウは
いつもよりさらに いつも通り＞
While Nitta was even more like himself than normal.
＜やっさんと福田さんは
いつもより楽しそうだった＞
Ya and Fukuda enjoyed themselves more than usual.
(古谷)ほんじゃ またな｡
京都に来ることあったら➡
Well, see you around.
If you're ever in Kyoto, give me a ring.
連絡くれや｡
四条でも案内したるわ｡
I'll show you around Shijo.
(福田)ハハハ…ありがとう｡
Thank you.
ホントに行っちゃうぞ！
ああ 来い来い！
I'll hold you to that.
Sure, just drop by.
気をつけて！
Have a safe trip.
＜やっさんは京都に帰り
福田さんは…＞
Ya returned to Kyoto.
As for Fukuda...
ゆっくり温泉巡りしたいなぁ｡
＜…と いい放ち➡
I feel like going on a hot springs tour.
And with that,
ぶらり温泉ひとり旅に出かけた＞
he set off on a trip by himself.
＜やっさんと福田さんの心境は
俺とは違うのだろうか…＞
It seemed Ya and Fukuda weren't taking this the way I was.
＜２人とも表情は軽かった＞
They looked relaxed.
ウッア～クゥ～…｡
Personally, I felt like there was something I should be doing.
《俺自身も 何かをやらなければと
思ってはいるのだが…》
《何をするかを
決められないでいた…》
But I couldn't figure out what it was.
ハ…ハ…ハックショイ！
ウゥ～ 寒い…｡
It's freezing...
まずは Ａ班の残った３人から
検討しましょう｡➡
First, we'll evaluate the three remaining Team A members.
最初に 意見の分かれる
南波君について｡➡
We'll begin with Nanba, who received mixed reviews.
Houston Bound
Itou Serika                  Mizoguchi Yamato              Shimizu Sanae
Nitta Reiji                     Teshima Yuuri               Morishima Shigeo
Ｂ班は 課題の成績
Ｃ班は毎日の投票を元に➡
Team B used their task scores, while Team C held a daily discussion and vote to select their two.
話し合いで２人を選びました｡
多少 もめる場面もありました｡➡
There was some bickering involved.
一方 Ａ班はジャンケンで決定｡
Meanwhile, Team A used rock-paper-scissors to decide.
Rock-paper-scissors?
(田沼)ジャンケンですか!?
(職員)ええ｡それを提案したのが
南波君です｡
Yes, and it was Nanba's idea.
それは 安定した心理状態での
発言だったんですか？
Was he mentally fit at the time?
(原田)それは これから
お見せする録画映像と➡
You can check the video footage and brain activity feed to see for yourself.
各種 数値データでご判断下さい｡
(職員)あ～ もうちょっとさ➡
Yeah, but seriously?
正当な決め方が
あったんじゃない？➡
Couldn't they have used a more rational method, like Teams B and C?
Ｂ班 Ｃ班みたいなさ｡➡
ちょっとわかんないよね｡
南波君の発想｡
I can't understand why Nanba would have proposed that idea.
(星加)そりゃそうですよ｡
Of course not.
Only the team members could really understand what went on
あの中で過ごした人の気持ちは
あの中でしか わかりません｡
inside that room.
Ahem.
(鶴見)ウホン！➡
過去の選抜を振り返ってみても
閉鎖ﾎﾞｯｸｽで過ごしたメンバーは➡
Historically speaking,
team members have always left the sealed boxes on good terms.
必ずと言っていいほど
仲良くなって出てくるんだよ｡➡
グリーンカードで
一時的に関係を乱しても➡
While the green cards typically cause rifts,
the bond among the members is generally stronger once they learn the truth.
カードの存在に気づいた時
彼らは前より団結力が強くなる｡➡
そういうもんだった｡
That has been standard.
(星加)今回 初めて➡
This was the first time
｢自分たちで２人を選ばせる｣と
いう最大の課題を与えましたが➡
we added the task of having team members
select the two candidates.
This caused more conflict than we anticipated.
これは予想以上に
各班の｢和｣を乱しました｡➡
ジャンケンが正当だったか
どうかは知りませんが➡
I don't know if rock-paper-scissors was a wholly legitimate solution.
ひとつだけ はっきりしたことが
あります｡➡
But one thing is clear.
２人を選び終えた後
すぐにあの中で➡
After choosing their two,
the only team
次に５人で会う打ち上げの
約束をしたのは…Ａ班だけです｡
that immediately promised to get together,
was Team A.
4 Days Later
"So there you go, Hibito.
《というわけだ 日々人｡
どうやら俺は 運をアメリカで➡
Looks like I used up all my luck in America.
使いきってしまったみたいだ》
(アポ)ハフ ハフ ハフ…｡
Without Apo,
《アポがいなけりゃ
ジｬンケンにも勝てやしねぇ…》
I can't even win a game of rock-paper-scissors."
消去 消去｡
Delete...
ハァ～ア～…｡
ウ～ム…｡
ボクシングものと宇宙ものか…｡
Boxing or space?
映画のセリフ
｢さあ ラッキー
パンチを繰り出していきます｣
Rocky throws a flurry of punches.
｢ラッキー パンチ当たり外れる｣
Rocky misses!
Rocky's fighting hard! Keeping up the pressure!
｢ラッキー強い！ま～だ強い！
ま～だいける～！｣
《やっぱりなぁ 俺の運は
アメリカで尽きてた…》
Yeah...
I used up all my luck in America...
《な～んで宇宙ものに
しなかったんだ｡➡
Why didn't I choose the space flick?
Well, it wouldn't have been much better...
まあ あれも
どうかと思うけど…》
《運なんて何を今さら…➡
Why am I worrying about my luck now?
基本の｢ついてない男｣に
戻っただけじゃねぇか》
I never had any luck to begin with.
《３次試験に行けたのだって…》
I only advanced to the third exam
《俺が消火器強盗を
捕まえたって話が➡
because I was on the news for catching that robber.
注目されたからだろうけど…》
And that was all Apo.
《ありゃあ アポのおかげだろ｡
忘れんなよ》
Don't forget.
《ダメだった時用の 日々人への
言い訳メールでも考えとくか》
I need to think of an excuse to tell Hibito when I fail.
Makabe Kenji
《ケンジ！》
Kenji!
Makabe
Kenji
Hey!
"Mu! Did you see the news?
｢ムッ君！ネットニュース見た!?➡
They announced the number of people going to Houston!
さっき ヒューストン行きの
人数が発表されてたよ！｣｡
(ﾒｰﾙ:ケンジの声)｢ＪＡＸＡの➡
According to JAXA's announcement,
発表によると 通過したのは８人で
内､女性が３人だって！｣｡
eight are going, three of whom are female!"
《８人!?》
Eight?
《ってことは 今まで受かった
６人に２人追加されたのか！➡
That means they added two additional people?
えっ？誰だ!?》
Who?
《えっ？ちょっと待て
女性が３人!?➡
Hold on...
Three of whom are female?
女性は あと北村さんしか
いないから 一人は確定だ…》
Kitamura's the only remaining female, so that's a no brainer.
《てことは…
あと１人じゃねぇか 男は！》
So they'll only choose one more man?
《残った男から あと１人…》
One man from the remaining candidates...
《んなもん…
ケンジしかいねぇだろ…》
It's gotta be Kenji...
＜その４時間後…➡
Four hours later,
ＪＡＸＡからの合否通知が
家に届いた＞
a JAXA notification arrived at my house.
＜俺にラッキーを
呼び込んでくれるアポは➡
Apo, my good luck charm, was still in America.
アメリカにいるままで…＞
＜俺がひとり
封筒を開けたころ…＞
While I was opening the envelope alone...
(カチッ カチッ カチッ…)
ワン！ワン！ワンワン…！
(南波日々人)う～ん…｡
(アポ)ワン！ワン！ワンワン…！
ん…おはよう アポ｡
Morning, Apo...
いま
未だ 返信ナシか…｡
Still no reply?
(オジー)寒いんだから
車で行きゃいいのに｡
When it's this cold, you should go by car.
寒み～から これで行くんだよ｡
I'm going by bike because it's cold.
ムッタから
まだメールとかないのか？
Have you heard from Mutta yet?
もう試験も
終わってる頃だろ｡
The test should be over by now.
Not yet.
ないねぇ｡
聞いたけど返事がない｡
I asked, but he hasn't replied.
ダ…ダメだったのかな？
D-Did he not make it?
何だよ オジー｡その残念そうな顔｡
Why do you look so disappointed, Ozzy?
さては また賭けてんな｡
えっ いやあの…｡
Were you gambling again?
Uh! U-Um...
まあ 結果が わかってるなら
ムッちゃんがメｰルくれなくても➡
Well, once the results arrive, Mom will give me a call,
even if Mu hasn't responded.
母ちゃんが
電話してきそうだからな｡
まだ わかんないのかもね｡
We still don't know yet.
じゃあ ２日ほど
アポ よろしくね～｡
Well, please look after Apo for me.
(オジー)オゥ…｡
Sure...
どうやら 私の勝ちだな｡
Looks like I win.
まだ わからんだろが｡
We don't know that yet.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)は～い キッズ達
ここでは静かにお願いね｡
Okay, kids.
Please remain quiet.
セス
今 CES-51のクルー達は
シミュレーターに入っててね➡
The CES-51 crew members are inside the simulator right now,
フライトプランを本番通りに
シミュレーションするところよ｡
practicing their flight plan.
[PC](管制官)
こちら 訓練担当｡これから
コムチェックを開始します｡
I will be your instructor.
Please initiate COMCHECK.
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)はい ｺﾑﾁｪｯｸ 来た～！
ｺﾐｭﾆｹｰｼｮﾝﾁｪｯｸの略ね｡➡
And now they're performing the COMCHECK.
That's short for communications check.
声が聞こえるか確認するの｡
They're making sure everyone can hear each other.
[PC]こちら ヒビト｡
コムチェックの準備できたよ｡
Hibito here.
COMCHECK is complete.
グッド！ヒビト｡こっちの声の
聞こえ具合はどうだ？
Good, Hibito.
Am I coming through clearly?
[PC]ファイブ･バイ･ファイブ｡
Five by five.
Did you hear that "five by five"?
はい ファイブ･バイ･ファイブ
来た～！聞こえてるって意味よ｡
It means "loud and clear."
知ってるよね｡
I already knew that.
Uh-huh.
このシミュレーションではね➡
This simulation covers everything
打ち上げから 地球離脱ステージ
とのドッキングとか➡
from launch until docking with the Earth Departure Stage.
Essentially, they'll spend forty-eight hours reviewing the entire procedure for traveling from Earth to the moon.
とりあえず 地球を離れて
月へ向かうまでの行程を➡
４８時間 ぶっ通しでやるワケよ｡
Forty-eight hours?
４８時間!?
あの中に➡
They have to stay in there forty-eight hours?
４８時間 ずっといるんですか？
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)そうよ｡
That's right.
僕 無理｡
トイレは ど～すんの？
I couldn't do it...
What if they need the bathroom?
あのさ オムツはいてんだよ｡
You realize they're wearing diapers.
≪え～ オムツ～!?≫
≪ヤダな～≫
What? Diapers?
That sounds gross.
ちょっと あんた達
私のトークを聞きなさい｡
Excuse me... Could you pay attention?
そもそも 私が
この仕事を始めたのは➡
The reason I started working here is because when I was your age, I knew a nice guy named Mike...
そうね あんた達くらいの頃➡
マイクっていうナイスガイと
付き合っててね…｡
早送り
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)ヒューストン…
こちら オリオン｡➡
Houston.
Orion.
かいせん
回旋プログラム 正常始動！
Roll program.
いいな～それ｡
俺にも言わしてよ フレディ｡
That sounds cool.
Let me say it once, Freddy.
ダメ～｡言いたきゃ
船長になれ ヒビト｡フフフ…｡
No way.
You have to become captain first, Hibito.
《フフッ 船長か…》
Captain, huh?
《それもまた遠い話だ》
That'll take a while...
《ここまで来たけど
まだまだ行きたい先がある》
I've made it here,
but I still have a ways to go.
《新たな目標が止まらない》
I keep finding new objectives.
《ムッちゃんが思ってるほど
俺もムッちゃんも 大差ねぇぞ》
Mu isn't as far behind
as he believes
that he is.
《俺らは２人ともまだ
宇宙へ向かってる途中だ》
We're both still working
to make it into space.
(女)わぁ 見て見て たっくん！
Look, Ta...
What?
高～い！スゴ～い！高～い！
We're up so high!
Wow! We're so high!
ホントだね｡車がゴミのようだね｡
Yeah.
The cars look like bugs.
《まわりを見れば
カップル 子連れ➡
Looking around,
we have a couple, a family, a couple, a couple.
カップル カップル…》
《そして ここに１組の…》
And then we have...
(福田)おお～！私は やっぱり➡
Wow!
I really like high places.
高い所が好きみたいだな
《無職の おっさん２人組》
...two unemployed men.
ほら 南波君｡
鳥が下を飛んでるよ｡
Look, Nanba...
Birds are flying below us.
ホントだ！
You're right.
(福田)南波君…｡
Nanba,
私はダメだったけど
不思議と落ち込んではいないよ｡
I failed to pass,
but oddly enough, I don't feel bad about it.
(福田)寝ても覚めても 宇宙とか
ロケットのことばかり➡
I can't help but think about space and rockets, whether I'm asleep or awake.
考えてしまう
どうしようもない性分でね➡
今は 次に自分が やるべきことで
頭がいっぱいなんだ｡
I'm busy thinking about what I'll do next.
え…？それは➡
Huh?
You're not talking about your hot springs tour, are you?
ぶらり温泉ひとり旅の
ことじゃなく？
温泉は もう行ってきたよ｡
I already finished that tour.
３日で十分だった｡実は…➡
Three days was enough for me.
Actually,
｢日本初の有人宇宙ロケットを
一緒に飛ばさないか｣ってね➡
a private company has invited me to help launch Japan's first manned rocket.
民間の企業に誘われたんだ｡
《この人は やっぱり
只者ではなかった》
He's definitely special.
＜福田さんの話によると➡
According to Fukuda, this private company is serious.
その民間企業というのが
ハンパじゃない＞
＜大企業を辞めた 若き
エンジニア達のベンチャーが➡
The new venture was started by young engineers who left corporate life to make space travel a reality.
自前の技術で 宇宙旅行を
実現しようとしているらしい＞
＜絵空事じゃない＞
It's no pipe dream.
(福田)みんな 寝ても覚めても➡
All of them are thinking about space and rockets, whether they're asleep or awake.
宇宙やロケットが
頭から離れない連中だ｡
血が騒ぐよ｡
I'm getting excited.
どうやら 私の夢も
まだ続いていくらしい｡
It looks like my dream hasn't ended yet.
(福田)今日は悪かったね
付き合ってもらって｡
Thanks for sharing your time today.
いやいや…ヒマですから 俺｡
Don't sweat it...
I have nothing else to do.
一度ゆっくり
君と話したくてね｡
I've been looking for a chance to chat with you.
お礼を言わなきゃと思ってた｡
I wanted to thank you.
Huh?
(福田)時計を壊したのが
私だと知っていたのに➡
You knew I broke the clock,
秘密にしててくれたことや➡
but you kept it a secret.
最後に２人を選ぶ時に
私にもチャンスをくれたこと｡➡
When we chose our two candidates at the end, you gave me a sporting chance.
本当に感謝してる｡
I really am grateful.
｢こういう人が
選ばれるのかもしれない｣ってさ➡
I had a feeling that you were what
そんな気がしてたんだよ｡
JAXA was looking for.
本当に そうなって良かった｡
I'm glad I was right.
ヒューストン行き おめでとう｡
Congratulations on making it to Houston.
We are pleased to inform you that you have passed the third astronaut selection exam.
ありがとう 福田さん｡
Thank you, Fukuda.
《いつになく うれしかった》
It was the happiest moment of my life.
《今までみたいに
運で残れた訳じゃなく➡
This time, it wasn't luck that got me through.
初めて自分自身が
認められたんだから》
For the first time, I was accepted for who I am.
《ただ…最後の１人が
俺ということは…》
However, if I'm the last candidate...
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)あ！来た!?➡
Oh, there it is...
ヒビト 来たよ！
ムッタから電話だ!!
Hibito, this is it!
You have a call from Mutta.
用件 聞いといて｡
Ask him what he wants.
(ｶﾚﾝ)いよいよね ヒビト｡
It's finally happened, Hibito.
聞こえるか ヒビト！➡
Can you hear me, Hibito?
おめでとう！
ムッタはヒューストンに来るぞ！
Congrats, Mutta's coming to Houston!
(ｶﾚﾝ)ワォ！
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)よ～し！
やったな!!
Yes!
Way to go!
＜選ばれた喜びと あり余る
やる気を かみしめながら➡
I was thrilled to be chosen and anxious to get started.
もう一方では
一番の友に言うべき言葉を➡
But at the same time,
I didn't know what I'd say to my best friend...
見つけられないでいた…＞
The lens inside my eyes
went completely out of focus when I saw you
The signs of love flooded the occipital lobe of my cerebrum
The words the left side of my brain produced
brought my vocal cords to reverberation
Vigorously my confession traversed my tongue
May I love you?
May I really love you?
May I be beside you? (The concentration of my hormones rose)
(Dopamine overwhelmed me)
Can I hold your hand? (My blood circulation powered up)
＜宇宙飛行士の最終試験のため➡
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#23 Father, Son, and Mutta Claus
I'm off to NASA, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, for the final astronaut selection exam.
ナサ
私はＮＡＳＡ ｱﾒﾘｶ航空宇宙局に
行くことに＞
＜でも ケンジは
どうして選ばれなかったんだ？＞
But why wasn't Kenji chosen?
＜何て声をかければいい？＞
What am I supposed to say to him?
(南波父)＜それよりムッタよ＞
＜えっ？＞
So, Mutta...
Hmm?
＜男なら 親父より稼げ！＞
A son should earn more than his father!
＜え～!?
それ 今 俺が無職だから？＞
What?
But I'm unemployed.
＜じゃあ…
まぁ バイトでもするか＞
Well, I guess I could find a part-time job...
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Father, Son, and Mutta Claus"
＜サンタクロースに 俺はなる！＞
I will become Santa Claus!
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
The long-awaited "Kounotori"
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真です！
ウヒョー！
Whee!